## **SUMMARY**

I'm a full stack software engineer specializing in both server-side and client-side JavaScript and the .NET framework. With over 7 years of professional experience, I have had the opportunity to work on projects that run the gambit from federal government projects and tools, to private business enterprise web applications, to building websites for digital marketing agencies, to working entrepreneurially as a freelance consultant, and now I am shifting into working full-time in Web3 and looking forward to contributing to build the future of the web with my next employer.

# **EXPERIENCE**

## Polyecho Labs Co-founder / CTO

Feb 2022 - Present • Global

- Polyecho is a Web3 product centered around generative music NFTs with royalties baked in. Users can upload stems (individual instruments within a track) to a Polyecho project, where others may listen and playback. Other collaborators can add stems onto the project to build up a song, which can then be minted as an NFT.
- All stems and NFT metadata is stored on IPFS via NFT.storage at Protocol Labs.
- The mint price is evenly distributed amongst all collaborators, and the NFT can be listed for sale on the secondary market. When a secodary sale is made, the seller receives 90% of the proceeds and the other 10% is split evenly amongst teh collaborators in the form of royalties, all on-chain
- This project started at the ETHDenver IRL hackathon which one first prize from Filecoin. We went on to build this
  during the ETHDenver virtual hackathon the following month and won top placements in the NFT category, top
  30 overall projects, and top 5 projects from celebrity judges. We're using the winnings to fund our treasury and
  support onboarding new producers and artists onto the platform.
- I have been responsible for building both the frontend and backend for the web application, the Solidity smart contracts, as well as oversight onto technical decisions for the project. This will be an ongoing project.
- Tech Used: Ethereum, Polygon, IPFS, Solidity, Next.js, React, MongoDB, Jest, Python

## Charter Communications Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2021 - Present • Greenwood Village, CO

- Providing technical insight and engineering support on the core design systems team. We author and make
  design decisions that impact the entire suite of Spectrum products at Charter, and I build the tech around it.
  Currently, I'm building out our new technical documentation site in TypeScript and Vue 3. I also optimize the
  web performance and accessibility of our design system components and help shape the developer experience
  for all product engineers utilizing our components across React, Angular, Vue, and vanilla JavaScript component
  libraries.
- \* Tech Used: TypeScript, Vue3, React, Angular, VuePress, Sass, Gitlab, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Jira

#### Architect of the Capitol Full Stack Software Engineer

Sept 2020 - May 2020 • Washington, DC (remote)

- I came into an existing monolithic app migration (used once every 2 years) from .NET 4.x to .NET Core 3.x and had to adapt to a new team unfamiliar with the app, where I became the "pointman". Since I worked on the app previously, I was the one with all the historical knowledge and context and provided insight to the team on data relationships, why decisions were made around code architecture, and to clarify expected application use cases.
- I helped speed up future schema migrations by writing many different SQL scripts to be used for every cycle (2y).
- I had a direct impact on the onboarding process for new hires and developers across the broader organization new to the codebase, by authoring all documentation for the new front end architecture and defined best practices and principles to follow.
- I impacted the efficiency of stakeholder feature demos and QA testing by creating SQL scripts to mimic specific
  application states, which were used by both developers and QA for testing bugs and setting up feature demos,
  resulting in a more seamless workflow and a happier client during demos.
- I optimized and improved the code quality by owning the rewriting of the client application from an MVC view-based approach to a SPA and upgraded to React 16.5, rewriting all class-based components to functional components with hooks, implemented the Context API for global storage and authored over 330 individual tests across 110 test suites to react 80% code coverage. Since I wrote the client app 2 years prior, it gave me the opportunity to catch all my oversights and apply newfound knowledge.
- Tech Used: .NET, C#, SQL, React, Jest, SignalR, Hangfire, React Testing Library, Sass, Bootstrap, ESLint, Prettier, Team Foundation Server

#### SKILLS

## Programming Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, Solidity, C# SQL, GraphQL HTML, CSS, YAML, XML

#### Frameworks & Tooling

Ethereum, Truffle, Hardhat, Ethers.js, Web3.js IPFS, Infura, Alchemy, The Graph .NET, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Apollo React, Vue, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Redux, React Native Jest, Mocha, React Testing Library, Enzyme, Cypress AWS, Git, CircleCl, Heroku, Webpack, TFS, Jira

#### Othe

Communication, project planning, team collaboration self-management, emotional intelligence, mentorship

#### Certifications

Certified ScrumMaster ScrumAlliance Certificate ID #355624

## **EDUCATION**

# SeedPaths

Aug 2014 - Oct 2014 • Denver, CO 8-week intensive software development bootcamp learning full stack, object-oriented programming in C#, .NET, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, SQL, Git

### Louisiana State University

Aug 2008 - May 2011 • Baton Rouge, LA Landscape Architecture & Communication Studies

### **ENTREPRENEURIAL**

# Polyecho Labs LLC

Feb 2022 – Present • Denver, CO I am a cofounder and CTO of a Web3 startup focused around generative music NFTs.

### Althea Web Services, LLC

June 2016 - Present • Denver, CO

I'm the sole-proprietor of this business, primarily used for freelancing or consulting work.

## Gloo, LLC Senior Software Engineer - Web

June 2019 - Sept 2020 • Boulder, CO

- I worked on the Accounts/Registration team for onboarding new users and organizations registering with the Gloo platform. We solved the problem for tracking where a new user's external origin was, and through logic, determining their proper destination to be, scaling for an SSO model across the platform's host of products. Our UIs had a direct impact on every user, optimizing the conversion rates for successful registrations through efficient user flows, registrations, password resets, verification codes via email, etc.
- As the only full-time employee web engineer on our team, I was responsible for ensuring our Gloo Web team policies and practices were being upheld through code reviews, guidance, and patience.
- I contributed to the internal Gloo Web team by authoring two NPM packages to implement custom Google Analytics and Facebook tags within our Next.js applications.
- I sped up our onboarding process for web contributors by spearheading a Naming Conventions Best Practices doc on front end code for React, Apollo GraphQL, Rosie, Jest, Next.js, etc. authoring it, coordinating with team members for input, and getting everyone to sign off on it, which we later adopted and included our onboarding docs for new hires or contractors.
- Tech Used: Typescript, Next.js, Apollo GraphQL, Express, CircleCl, Heroku, Docker, Kubernetes, Jest, Cypress, React Testing Library, Material UI, Formik, Rollbar

### Architect of the Capitol Full Stack Software Engineer

Mar 2018 - June 2019 • Washington, DC (remote)

## Project - Compass

- Îled the front end development during a redesign of the internal SharePoint intranet for employees about organizational news, events, and other important information.
- I optimized and reduced the time and stress for content creators within the organization by planning, developing, and launching an internal tool for creating custom SharePoint content, catered to the site. This was used by internal employees that were responsible for creating events, promotionals, articles, image uploads, etc within Compass.
- I helped mentor other team members on pieces of code / development concepts when the time was needed.

## **Project - Senate Suites**

- I owned the client application development during an enterprise app redesign in .NET, migrating from an MVC architecture with views written in Razor to views written in React. I leveraged Redux for state management and Webpack for modular bundle sizes, ensuring only proper bundles were loaded for relative pages within the app.
- I ushered in and implemented a testing strategy in Jest and Enzyme, resulting in a test coverage of 78% of all client code. Previously, there were no tests implemented at all.
- 🕨 I also supported migrating features from ColdFusion into .NET, and implemented WebAPIs for a RESTful approach, resulting in a faster and less buggy app.
- I worked directly with stakeholders of the project, organizing and planning feature work, tech debt, and long term trajectory, while building up client communication skills.
- Tech Used: C#, .NET, SQL, React, TypeScript, Redux, Jest, Enzyme, jQuery, SharePoint, CAML, Webpack, ESLint, Less

# **EXPERIENCE** (continued)

#### Evolver, Inc. Front End Software Engineer

Apr 2017 - Mar 2018 • Centennial, CO

- I dramatically improved the user experience for over 10,000 users by optimizing client code and refactoring a .NET MVC web app with jQuery to using React and Redux.
- I brought in shipping confidence for the app and improved our deployment pipeline by implementing a testing harness in Jest and Enzyme covering over 75% of client code, configuring linting with ESLint and formatting with Prettier for overall code quality.
- Tech Used: C#, .NET, React, ES6 JavaScript, CSS, Sass, Webpack, Redux, Jest, Énzyme, Prettier, Jira, jQuery

### Crawford & O'Brien Lead Web Developer

Sep 2015 - Apr 2017 • Tempe, AZ (remote)

- I served as the lead developer for a digital marketing agency performing any and all tech related tasks for over 40 clients, including but not limited to: development of Wordpress and Shopify sites with custom themes, continued client support requests, DNS and content migrations, emails, security, backups, site speed optimizations, SEO, etc.
- I built up personal communication skills by working directly with the clients to find out their needs and accomplishing the tasks needed to meet those. I was the main point of contact for direct requests for their websites, and I interacted with them on a 1:1 basis.
- As our department lead, I directed and managed 3 junior developers by delegating tasks and implementing, documenting and overseeing our processes of web development.
- Tech Used: WordPress, PHP, Shopify, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Google Analytics, WooCommerce, Yoast SEO, Trello

#### Access-Now Web Developer/Designer

Dec 2014 - Jan 2015 • Denver, CC

- \* As a contributor, I designed and built dynamic, responsive websites and custom logos and marketing materials for a digital marketing agency. I worked directly with clients.
- Tech Used: WordPress, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, cPanel, Plesk, Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, and Illustrator

References are available upon request. You can always check out my LinkedIn testimonials & endorsements in the meantime.